<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ruby | Mischa Taylor's Coding Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://misheska.com/blog/categories/ruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://misheska.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-25T06:36:34-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://misheska.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mischa Taylor]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using pik to manage multiple versions of Ruby on Windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://misheska.com/blog/2013/03/10/using-pik-to-manage-multiple-versions-of-ruby-on-windows/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-10T18:09:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://misheska.com/blog/2013/03/10/using-pik-to-manage-multiple-versions-of-ruby-on-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Out of the box, Ruby does not provide a mechanism to support multiple installed
versions.  <code>pik</code> is a third-party tool that can be used to switch
between multiple versions of the Ruby interpreter on Windows.</p>

<h1>Install Ruby</h1>

<p>Install at least one Ruby interpreter environment using the RubyInstaller
from <a href="http://rubyinstaller.org">http://rubyinstaller.org</a>.  While pik can
install some versions of Ruby, the versions of Ruby it knows to install is
quite limited, and it is just much easier to use RubyInstaller for Windows
to install them.</p>

<p>The choice of Ruby environments to install is up to you.  I have the latest
version of 1.9.3 installed as my main development environment, and Ruby 2.0.0
to play around with the next generation of the language.  When you install
Ruby, do not add the Ruby executables to your PATH or associate .rb/.rbw
files with the Ruby installation (the default choice) - <code>pik</code> will
manage this setting:</p>

<p><img src="/images/rubyinstaller.png" alt="Ruby Installer" /></p>

<h1>Installing pik</h1>

<p>Download the latest .MSI installer from <a href="https://github.com/vertiginous/pik/downloads">pik downloads on github</a>
(as of this writing <a href="https://github.com/downloads/vertiginous/pik/pik-0.3.0.pre.msi">0.3.0</a>) and run the Pik Setup Wizard - the default options are fine:</p>

<p><img src="/images/pikinstaller.png" alt="Pik Installer" /></p>

<p>You can verify that <code>pik</code> installed properly by running the
following in a Command Prompt:</p>

<pre><code>&gt; pik --version
pik 0.3.0.pre on Microsoft Windows [Version 6.1.7601]
by Gordon Thiesfeld (gthiesfeld@gmail.com)
</code></pre>

<h1>Registering Ruby environments with pik</h1>

<p>Use the <code>pik add</code> command to register your installed ruby
environments with pik.  For example, I have Ruby 1.8.7, 1.9.3, and 2.0.0
installed on my Windows development box, so I typed the following in a
Command Prompt:</p>

<pre><code>&gt; pik add C:\Ruby187\bin
INFO: Adding:  [ruby-]1.8.7-p371
      Located at:  C:\Ruby187\bin

&gt; pik add C:\Ruby193\bin
INFO: Adding:  [ruby-]1.9.3-p392
      Located at:  C:\Ruby193\bin

&gt; pik add C:\Ruby200\bin
INFO: Adding:  [ruby-]2.0.0-p0
      Located at:  C:\Ruby2000\bin
</code></pre>

<p>Use the <code>pik list</code> command to list all the ruby interpreters
registered with pik:</p>

<pre><code>&gt; pik list
   ruby-1.8.7-p371
   ruby-1.9.3-p392
   ruby-2.0.0-p0
</code></pre>

<h1>Set a default Ruby</h1>

<p>The <code>pik use</code> command will allow you to switch between your
registered ruby interpreters:</p>

<pre><code>&gt; pik use ruby-2.0.0-p0
&gt; ruby -v
ruby 2.0.0p0 (2013-02-024) [i386-mingw32]
</code></pre>

<p>Add the <code>--default</code> parameter to set one version as the default:</p>

<pre><code>&gt; pik use ruby-1.9.3-p392 --default
</code></pre>

<p>You can use the <code>pik default</code> command to switch to this version:</p>

<pre><code>&gt; pik default
&gt; ruby -v
ruby 1.9.3p392 (2013-02-022) [i386-mingw32]
</code></pre>

<p>Unfortunately when you open a new command prompt, pik is not automatically
loaded, so you will notice that there is no default ruby loaded:</p>

<p><img src="/images/rubynewcommand.png" alt="Ruby not found'" /></p>

<p>Either run the <code>pik default</code> command to load pik (and the
default ruby interpreter) or add one particular Ruby interpreter to your
user or system PATH environment variable (via <code>Control Panel -&gt; System
-&gt; Advanced -&gt; Environment Variables….</code>):</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/environment1.png" width="350" height="394" title="'Environment control panel'" >
<img class="right" src="/images/environment2.png" width="350" height="394" title="'User PATH'" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Try out Sensu Monitoring using Virtual Box, Vagrant and Chef]]></title>
    <link href="http://misheska.com/blog/2013/02/28/try-out-sensu-monitoring-using-virtual-box%2C-vagrant-and-chef/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-28T22:54:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://misheska.com/blog/2013/02/28/try-out-sensu-monitoring-using-virtual-box,-vagrant-and-chef</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been using Sensu Monitoring in production for about three to four months
now.  It's a nice, lightweight monitoring framework, designed with the cloud
in mind and for use with modern configuration management frameworks like
Chef and Puppet.  For more information on Sensu, check out the article
<a href="https://github.com/sensu/sensu/wiki">Why Sonian created Sensu (by Sean Porter)</a>
and the associated articles and links on the <a href="https://github.com/sensu/sensu/wiki">Sensu Wiki</a></p>

<p>In this article, I'm going to present a quick overview on how to test and
evaluate Sensu using the <a href="https://github.com/sensu/sensu-chef">Sensu Chef Cookbook</a>
Through the magic of Oracle VirtualBox and Vagrant, combined with Chef, you
can quickly deploy Sensu to a local virtual machine instance, and kick the
tires on Sensu to evaluate whether or not it is a good monitoring solution
for you.  These instructions apply to Mac OS X, Linux, and/or Windows for
the host operating system.</p>

<h1>Install VirtualBox</h1>

<p>VirtualBox is an open source virtualization platform, similar to VMWare
Fusion/Workstation that runs on Mac OS X, Linux and Windows (and a few more
platforms).  While I personally prefer VMWare Fusion to VirtualBox (VirtualBox
can be a bit flakey at times), a lot of automation around VirtualBox has been
developed within the Chef community, which impossible to ignore.  Fortunately
on both Mac OS X and Linux, VirtualBox can peacefully coexist with VMWare
Fusion/Workstation (NOTE: If you use KVM virtualization on Linux, VirtualBox
can also coexist, but you need to be careful not to run VirtualBox and KVM
images simultaneously).</p>

<p>Just download and run the VirtualBox installer from the <a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads">VirtualBox download
page</a>.  Just download and install
the latest 4.2.x version of VirtualBox.  Make sure you save the VirtualBox
installer as it comes with an uninstall tool, should you wish to remove
VirtualBox at some point in the future.</p>

<h1>Install Vagrant</h1>

<p>After installing VirtualBox, next install Vagrant.  Vagrant is an automation
framework for VirtualBox.  Grab the latest Vagrant installer for your OS from
the <a href="http://downloads.vagrantup.com/">Vagrant Downloads page</a> and run install.
On Mac OS X and Windows, the Vagrant install will automatically add the Vagrant
binaries to your PATH, on Linux, you will need to manually add
<code>/opt/vagrant/bin</code> per the <a href="http://docs.vagrantup.com/v1/docs/getting-started/index.html">Getting Started with Vagrant docs</a>.</p>

<h1>Download the sensu-chef cookbook</h1>

<p>Grab the latest version of the sensu-chef cookbook from GitHub by running
the following command:</p>

<pre><code>git clone https://github.com/sensu/sensu-chef.git
</code></pre>

<h1>Install Ruby &amp; RubyGems</h1>

<p>The sensu-chef cookbook requires Ruby &amp; RubyGems.</p>

<p>On Mac OS X and Linux, I strongly recommend that you use either RVM or Rbenv
to make sure that you are using the latest version of Ruby instead of whatever
version of Ruby your system installs by default.</p>

<p>See my previous articles on <a href="http://misheska.com/blog/2013/02/24/using-rvm-to-manage-multiple-versions-of-ruby/">RVM</a> or <a href="http://misheska.com/blog/2013/02/24/using-rbenv-to-manage-multiple-versions-of-ruby/">Rbenv</a>.  NOTE: If you don't
know whether or not to decide between RVM or Rbenv, go with RVM.</p>

<h1>Patch chef-sensu Vagrantfile</h1>

<p>As of this writing, the <code>Vagrantfile</code> included in
<code>sensu-chef/examples</code> will not set up the VM properly and the
Chef run will fail with the following error:</p>

<pre><code>[default] Running chef-solo...
stdin: is not a tty
[Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:28:06 +0000] INFO: *** Chef 0.10.8 ***
[Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:28:06 +0000] INFO: Setting the run_list to ["recipe[monitor::master]", "recipe[monitor::redis]", "recipe[monitor::rabbitmq]"] from JSON
[Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:28:06 +0000] INFO: Run List is [recipe[monitor::master], recipe[monitor::redis], recipe[monitor::rabbitmq]]
[Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:28:06 +0000] INFO: Run List expands to [monitor::master, monitor::redis, monitor::rabbitmq]
[Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:28:06 +0000] INFO: Starting Chef Run for ubuntu-1204-i386
[Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:28:06 +0000] INFO: Running start handlers
[Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:28:06 +0000] INFO: Start handlers complete.
[Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:28:07 +0000] ERROR: Running exception handlers
[Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:28:07 +0000] ERROR: Exception handlers complete
[Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:28:07 +0000] FATAL: Stacktrace dumped to /tmp/vagrant-chef-1/chef-stacktrace.out
[Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:28:07 +0000] FATAL: NoMethodError: undefined method `default_action' for #&lt;Class:0x8decb20&gt;
Chef never successfully completed! Any errors should be visible in the
</code></pre>

<p>output above. Please fix your recipes so that they properly complete.</p>

<p>I've created a revised <code>Vagrantfile</code> which fixes this issue.
Download this amended version and copy it in place of
<code>sensu-client/examples/Vagrantfile</code></p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/5063291.js?file=Vagrantfile'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>#require 'berkshelf/vagrant'

Vagrant::Config.run do |config|
  config.vm.box = &quot;ubuntu-1204-i386&quot;
  config.vm.box_url = &quot;http://vagrant.sensuapp.org/ubuntu-1204-i386.box&quot;

  config.vm.customize [
    &quot;modifyvm&quot;, :id,
    &quot;--name&quot;, &quot;Sensu Stack&quot;,
    &quot;--memory&quot;, &quot;1024&quot;
  ]

  config.vm.provision :shell, :inline =&gt; &quot;apt-get install -y curl&quot;
  config.vm.provision :shell, :inline =&gt; &quot;curl -L https://www.opscode.com/chef/install.sh | bash&quot;

  config.vm.forward_port 8080, 8080
  config.vm.forward_port 9000, 9000

  config.vm.provision :chef_solo do |chef|
    chef.cookbooks_path = &quot;cookbooks&quot;
    chef.data_bags_path = &quot;data_bags&quot;
    chef.add_recipe &quot;monitor::master&quot;
    chef.add_recipe &quot;monitor::redis&quot;
    chef.add_recipe &quot;monitor::rabbitmq&quot;
  end
end
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<h1>Install Ruby DevKit (Windows)</h1>

<p>The sensu-chef recipe is dependent on the json gem.  On Windows, you will get
the following error if you do not have the proper Ruby DevKit installed:</p>

<pre><code>Installing json (1.7.7)
Gem::InstallError: The 'json' native gem requires installed build tools.
</code></pre>

<p>Go to <a href="http://rubyinstaller.org/downloads">http://rubyinstaller.org/downloads</a>
and refer to the <em>Which Development Kit?</em> section of the web page about which
DevKit you need to install.</p>

<p>Download the appropriate DevKit toolkit, extract it and run the following
in a Command Prompt:</p>

<pre><code>&gt; ruby dk.rb init
[INFO] found RubyInstaller v1.9.3 at C:/Ruby193

Initialization complete! Please review and modify the auto-generated
'config.yml' file to ensure it contains the root directories to all
of the installed Rubies you want enhanced by the DevKit.

&gt; ruby dk.rb install
[INFO] Updating convenience notice gem override for 'C:/Ruby193'
[INFO] Installing 'C:/Ruby193/lib/ruby/site_ruby/devkit.rb'
</code></pre>

<h1>Create the sensu-chef virtual machine</h1>

<p>Run the following commands to create the sensu-chef virtual machine:</p>

<pre><code>cd sensu-chef/examples
gem install bundler
# On Windows, restart the command prompt before running 'bundle install' as
# gem install will reset the PATH
bundle install
librarian-chef install
vagrant up
</code></pre>

<p>If all goes well, the <code>chef-solo</code> run should have succeeded, and
you should be able to view the Sensu dashboard by going to the following URL
with the username <code>admin</code> and the password <code>secret</code>:
<a href="http://localhost:8080">http://localhost:8080</a></p>

<p><img src="/images/sensudashboard.png" alt="Sensu Dashboard" /></p>

<p>If this is successful, on Mac OX and Linux, just run the following command to
log in to your newly-created virtual machine instance:</p>

<pre><code>vagrant ssh
</code></pre>

<p>On Windows, run the following command (or use a visual SSH client like PuTTY):</p>

<pre><code>ssh vagrant@127.0.0.1 -p 2222 -i C:/Users/misheska/.vagrant.d/insecure_private_key
</code></pre>

<p>And refer to the <a href="https://github.com/sensu/sensu/wiki">Sensu wiki</a> on how
to experiment with various configuration options.</p>

<p>When you are done playing with the test VM, run the following command to
destroy the VM:</p>

<pre><code>vagrant destroy
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Rbenv to manage multiple versions of Ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://misheska.com/blog/2013/02/24/using-rbenv-to-manage-multiple-versions-of-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T22:47:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://misheska.com/blog/2013/02/24/using-rbenv-to-manage-multiple-versions-of-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Out of the box, Ruby does not provide a mechanism to support multiple
installed versions.  Compounding this issue, the default system-installed
version of Ruby for most versions of Linux/Mac OS X tend to be quite old.
For example, even in the latest version of Mac OS X Mountain Lion, the
system-wide version of Ruby is over five years old (ruby 1.8.7).  Most
developers prefer to use a newer version of Ruby installed in their home
directory and to leave the default systemwide version of Ruby untouched.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/sstephenson/rbenv/">Rbenv</a> makes managing multiple
versions of Ruby easy.  Rbenv is a lightweight alternative to
<a href="http://rvm.io">Ruby Version Manager (RVM)</a>.  Rbenv does not include
any mechanism to install Ruby or manage gems, like with RVM.</p>

<p>Rbenv is supported on Linux and Mac OS X.  Rbenv doesn't work on Windows.
For Windows, <a href="https://github.com/vertiginous/pik">Pik</a> is an Rbenv alternative.</p>

<p>NOTE: Rbenv is incompatible with RVM because RVM overrides the
<code>gem</code> command with a function.  If you want to switch to Rbenv,
make sure you uninstall RVM first.  Run the following commands to uninstall
RVM:</p>

<pre><code>$ rvm implode
$ gem uninstall rvm
</code></pre>

<p>Then remove/comment out the RVM loader line in <code>.bash_profile</code>
and/or <code>.bashrc</code></p>

<h1>How to Install Rbenv on Mac OS X</h1>

<p>First you'll need to install a C compiler to build Ruby from source.  Just
download and install the latest version of Xcode from the App Store, if you
don't have it installed already.  Also make sure you install the <em>Command Line
Tools</em> by choosing the menu item <code>Xcode -> Preferences...</code> and click
on the <em>Downloads</em> tab.  Click on the <em>Install</em> button to download the
Command Line Tools.
<img src="/images/xcodecommandline.png" alt="Xcode Command Line Tools" /></p>

<p>Next, you'll need to install the Homebrew package manager to get all the
dependencies needed to compile Ruby from source.  While you could manage
these dependencies by hand, using a package manager is a better idea, as
package managers know how to uninstall what they install.</p>

<p>Run the following command to install Homebrew:</p>

<pre><code>ruby -e "$(curl -fsSL https://raw.github.com/mxcl/homebrew/go)"
</code></pre>

<p>Run <code>brew doctor</code> and address any issues it discovers.  When
all is well, you should see:</p>

<pre><code>$ brew doctor
Your system is raring to brew.
</code></pre>

<p>Next, install the additional dependencies to compile Ruby from source:</p>

<pre><code># For update-system
brew update
brew tap homebrew/dupes
# For ruby
brew install apple-gcc42
</code></pre>

<p>And now install <code>rbenv</code> and the <code>ruby-build</code> plugin:</p>

<pre><code>brew update
brew install rbenv
brew install ruby-build
</code></pre>

<p>Add <code>rbenv init</code> to your shell to enable shims and autocompletion:</p>

<pre><code>$ echo 'eval "$(rbenv init -)"' &gt;&gt; $HOME/.bash_profile
$ source ~/.bash_profile
</code></pre>

<p>Set the latest version of ruby to be the default version of ruby</p>

<pre><code>$ rbenv global 1.9.3-p392
</code></pre>

<p>Rebuild the shim executable</p>

<pre><code>$ rbenv rehash
</code></pre>

<p>You'll need to run <code>rbenv rehash</code> every time you install a new
version of Ruby or install a new gem.</p>

<p>Verify the ruby install</p>

<pre><code>$ ruby -v
ruby 1.9.3p392 (2013-02-22 revision 39386) [x86_64-darwin12.3.0]
</code></pre>

<h1>How to Upgrade Rbenv on Mac OS X</h1>

<p>To upgrade rbenv via homebrew:</p>

<pre><code>$ brew update
$ brew upgrade rbenv
$ brew upgrade ruby-build
</code></pre>

<h1>How to Remove Rbenv on Mac OS X</h1>

<p>Uninstall the packages you installed via homebrew:</p>

<pre><code>brew uninstall rbenv
brew uninstall ruby-build
</code></pre>

<p>And remove the following directory:</p>

<pre><code>rm -rf $HOME/.rbenv
</code></pre>

<p>And remember to remove whatever you added to <code>$HOME/.bash_profile</code></p>

<h1>How to Install RVM on Linux</h1>

<p>Make sure the prerequisite packages are installed.  For Ubuntu:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo apt-get install build-essential git
</code></pre>

<p>Download the rbenv source distribution to
$HOME/.rbenv:</p>

<pre><code>$ git clone git://github.com/sstephenson/rbenv.git $HOME/.rbenv
</code></pre>

<p>Add $HOME/.rbenv/bin to your $PATH</p>

<pre><code>$ echo 'export PATH="$HOME/.rbenv/bin:$PATH"' &gt;&gt; $HOME/.bashrc
</code></pre>

<p>Add <code>rbenv init</code> to your shell to enable shims and autocompletion:</p>

<pre><code>$ echo 'eval "$(rbenv init -)"' &gt;&gt; $HOME/.bashrc
</code></pre>

<p>Restart shell as a login shell so that the PATH changes take effect:</p>

<pre><code>$ exec $SHELL -l
</code></pre>

<p>Install the <code>ruby-build</code> plugin, which provides an
<code>rbenv install</code> command to simplify the process of compiling
and install new Ruby versions:</p>

<pre><code>$ git clone git://github.com/sstephenson/ruby-build.git $HOME/.rbenv/plugins/ruby-build
</code></pre>

<p>Install the latest version of ruby (at the time of this writing 1.9.3-p392)</p>

<pre><code>$ rbenv install 1.9.3-p392
</code></pre>

<p>Rebuild the shim executable</p>

<pre><code>$ rbenv rehash
</code></pre>

<p>You'll need to run <code>rbenv rehash</code> every time you install a new
version of Ruby or install a new gem.</p>

<p>Set the latest version of ruby to be the default version of ruby</p>

<pre><code>$ rbenv global 1.9.3-p392
</code></pre>

<p>Verify the ruby install</p>

<pre><code>$ ruby -v
</code></pre>

<h1>How to Upgrade Rbenv on Linux</h1>

<p>Since Rbenv is a Git repository, upgrading is just a matter of refreshing the
source:
<code>
$ cd $HOME/.rbenv
$ git pull
</code></p>

<h1>How to Remove Rbenv on Linux</h1>

<p>To uninstall/remove Rbenv, remove the following directory:
<code>
rm -rf $HOME/.rbenv
</code></p>

<p>And remember to remove whatever you added to <code>$HOME/.bash_profile</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using RVM to manage multiple versions of Ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://misheska.com/blog/2013/02/24/using-rvm-to-manage-multiple-versions-of-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T19:34:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://misheska.com/blog/2013/02/24/using-rvm-to-manage-multiple-versions-of-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Out of the box, Ruby does not provide a mechanism to support multiple
installed versions.  Compounding this issue, the default system-installed
version of Ruby for most versions of Linux/Mac OS X tend to be quite old.
For example, even in the latest version of Mac OS X Mountain Lion, the
system-wide version of Ruby is over five years old (ruby 1.8.7).  Most
developers prefer to use a newer version of Ruby installed in their home
directory and to leave the default systemwide version of Ruby untouched.</p>

<p><a href="http://rvm.io">Ruby Version Manager (RVM)</a>  makes installing multiple
versions of Ruby easy.  RVM also supports partitioning of Ruby gem installs
via a feature called gemsets in order to avoid versioning conflicts.  However,
with the advent of <a href="http://gembundler.com">Bundler</a> most developers tend to
prefer using Bundler as the preferred way for managing gems at the
application level.</p>

<p>RVM is supported on Linux and Mac OS X.  RVM doesn't work on Windows.
For Windows, <a href="https://github.com/vertiginous/pik">Pik</a> is an RVM alternative.</p>

<h1>How to Install RVM on Mac OS X</h1>

<p>First, you'll need to install a C compiler to build Ruby from source.  Just
download and install the latest version of Xcode from the App Store, if you
don't have it already.  Also make sure you install the <em>Command Line Tools</em>
by choosing the menu item <code>Xcode -> Preferences...</code> and click
on the <em>Downloads</em> tab.  Click on the <em>Install</em> button to download the
Command Line Tools.
<img src="/images/xcodecommandline.png" alt="Xcode Command Line Tools" /></p>

<p>Next, you'll need to install the Homebrew package manager.  RVM will
automatically download all dependencies if a package manager is installed.
Run the following command to install Homebrew:</p>

<pre><code>ruby -e "$(curl -fsSL https://raw.github.com/mxcl/homebrew/go)"
</code></pre>

<p>Run <code>brew doctor</code> and address any issues it discovers.  When
all is well, you should see:</p>

<pre><code>$ brew doctor
Your system is raring to brew.
</code></pre>

<p>After Xcode and Homebrew are installed, you can install RVM with the following
commands:</p>

<pre><code>$ \curl -#L https://get.rvm.io | bash -s stable
$ source $HOME/.rvm/scripts/rvm
</code></pre>

<p>Run <code>rvm requirements</code> and do what it says to install the additional
dependencies.  On my system, I ran the following:</p>

<pre><code># For update-system
brew update
brew tap homebrew/dupes
# For rvm
brew install apple-gcc42
</code></pre>

<p>Next, build and install the latest version of Ruby by running the following
(this will take a long time):</p>

<pre><code>$ rvm install 1.9.3
$ rvm use 1.9.3
$ rvm rubygems latest
</code></pre>

<p>Verify the RVM install by running the following commands:</p>

<pre><code>$ rvm -h
$ rvm list
$ rvm use 1.9.3
</code></pre>

<p>To ensure that the newer Ruby 1.9.3 is used by default instead of the
system 1.8.7 version, run the following command:</p>

<pre><code>$ rvm use 1.9.3 --default
</code></pre>

<p>If you'd like to manage RVM with a GUI, check out <a href="http://jewelrybox.unfiniti.com/">JewelryBox</a>:</p>

<p><img src="/images/jewelrybox.png" alt="Jewelry Box" /></p>

<h1>Installing Ruby 1.8.7 from source on Mac OS X</h1>

<p>For legacy GUI support, Ruby 1.8.7 has some dependencies on tcl/tk, which
Mountain Lion no longer installs by default (now that X11 is an optional
install).  To compile Ruby 1.8.7 without tcl/tk support, use the following
command overrides on <code>rvm install</code>:</p>

<pre><code>rvm install 1.8.7 --with-gcc=clang --without-tcl --without-tk
</code></pre>

<p>To compile Ruby 1.8.7 with tcl/tk support, install X11 via
<a href="http://xquartz.macosforge.org/landing">http://xquartz.macosforge.org/landing</a>
then compile Ruby 1.8.7 with the following:</p>

<pre><code>export CPPFLAGS=-I/opt/X11/include
CC=/usr/local/bin/gcc-4.2 rvm install 1.8.7
</code></pre>

<h1>Installing Ruby 2.0.0 from source on Mac OS X</h1>

<p>As of this writing, the current stable version of rvm (1.18.18) errors out with
a message about not being able to validate the rubygems-2.0.3.  To fix,
download the latest version of RVM like so:</p>

<pre><code># get rid of the unsuccessful installation
$ rvm remove 2.0.0
# download the latest version of RVM
$ rvm get head
$ rvm install 2.0.0
</code></pre>

<h1>How to Remove RVM on Mac OS X</h1>

<p>Should you want to uninstall/remove RVM, it's pretty easy.  First, run
the following commands:</p>

<pre><code>$ rvm implode
$ gem uninstall rvm
</code></pre>

<p>Then just follow the instructions from <code>rvm implode</code>:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Delete the following files, if they exist:
<code>/etc/rvmrc</code>
<code>$HOME/.rvmrc</code></p></li>
<li><p>Also, remove the lines sourcing RVM scripts from
<code>$HOME/.bash_profile</code> <code>/etc/zprofile</code> and
<code>/etc/profile.d/rvm.sh</code> if they exist.  (A reboot doesn't hurt
after you do this, just to make sure).</p></li>
</ul>


<p>To uninstall Homebrew, run the following:</p>

<pre><code>cd `brew --prefix`
brew install libtool
rm -rf Cellar
rm `git ls-files`
rm -r Library/Homebrew Library/Aliases Library/Formula Library/Contributions
rm -rf .git
rm -rf ~/Library/Caches/Homebrew
</code></pre>

<h1>How to Install RVM on Linux</h1>

<p>RVM installation is more straightforward on Linux, as the Ruby source was
designed for the GCC compiler that ships with any Linux distribution.</p>

<p>First install <code>curl</code>, so that you can fetch the RVM script.
For Ubuntu, run
the following command:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo apt-get install curl
</code></pre>

<p>For RedHat/CentOS:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo yum install curl
</code></pre>

<p>With curl installed, run the RVM install with the following commands:</p>

<pre><code>$ \curl -#L https://get.rvm.io | bash -s stable
$ source $HOME/.rvm/scripts/rvm
</code></pre>

<p>Run the <code>rvm requirements</code> command to get rvm to display the
commands to install the other dependent packages for compiling Ruby from
source:</p>

<pre><code>$ rvm requirements
...
# For Ruby / Ruby HEAD (MRI, Rubinius, &amp; REE), install the following:
ruby: /usr/bin/apt-get install build-essential openssl libreadline6 libreadline6-dev 
curl git-core zlib1g zlib1g-dev libssl-dev libyaml-dev libsqlite3-dev sqlite3 libxml2-dev
libxslt-dev autoconf libc6-dev ncurses-dev automake libtool bison subversion pkg-config
</code></pre>

<p>Run the appropriate command for your Linux distribution to install the
prerequisite packages.  For example, on Ubuntu, you would run:</p>

<pre><code>sudo apt-get install build-essential openssl libreadline6 libreadline6-dev \
curl git-core zlib1g zlib1g-dev libssl-dev libyaml-dev libsqlite3-dev sqlite3 \
libxml2-dev libxslt-dev autoconf libc6-dev ncurses-dev automake libtool bison  \
subversion pkg-config
</code></pre>

<p>Next build and install Ruby 1.9.3 (this will take awhile):</p>

<pre><code>$ rvm install 1.9.3
$ rvm use 1.9.3
$ rvm rubygems latest
</code></pre>

<p>Verify rvm install:</p>

<pre><code>$ rvm -h
$ rvm list
$ rvm use 1.9.3
</code></pre>

<h1>How to Remove RVM on Linux</h1>

<p>Should you want to uninstall/remove RVM, it's pretty easy.  First, run
the following commands:</p>

<pre><code>$ rvm implode
$ gem uninstall rvm
</code></pre>

<p>Then just follow the instructions from <code>rvm implode</code>:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Delete the following files, if they exist:
<code>/etc/rvmrc</code>
<code>$HOME/.rvmrc</code></p></li>
<li><p>Also, remove the lines sourcing RVM scripts from
<code>$HOME/.bash_profile</code> <code>/etc/zprofile</code> and
<code>/etc/profile.d/rvm.sh</code> if they exist.  (A reboot doesn't hurt
after you do this, just to make sure).</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
